Aldilas Achmad Nursetyo, M.D., M.S.

SUMMARY OF EXPERIENCE

Since 2015, Aldilas has been actively provide contribution and development for Indonesia Health Information System both at national and regional level, either academically through publications or direct consultancy. He has experience in developing monitoring and evaluation system in National Family Planning Coordinating Agency (BKKBN) and strengthening national disease surveillance system, especially for early warning and response system (EWARS). Recently he also active as Technical Working Group member for Indonesia National Health Information development. He also experienced in research methodology, either quantitative or qualitative methodology, while demonstrating excelence scientific writing and publication experience. Currently, he is active as researcher in Center for Health Policy and Management, Universitas Gadjah Mada, Indonesia.

EDUCATION

Taipei Medical University, M.S. Biomedical Informatics

2017-2019

Universitas Muhammadiyah Yogyakarta, M.D.

2013-2015

Universitas Muhammadiyah Yogyakarta, Bachelor of Medicine 2007-2012

EMPLOYMENT

ASEAN Biodiaspora Virtual Center

Technical Officer 2023-present

bla bla bla

World Bank Group

Consultant 2021-present

Center for Tropical Medicine, Universitas Gadjah Mada

Researcher 2020-present

Center for Health Policy & Management, Universitas Gadjah Mada

Researcher 2016-present

Apotek Viva Generik

General Practitioner 2020-2021

International Center for Health Information Technology, Taipei Medical University

Research Assistant 2018-2019

RSUD Inche Abdoel Moeis, Kota Samarinda

Internship Medical Doctor 2015-2016

1

1/4

ORGANIZATION

| Medical Student Association, Universitas Muhammadiyah Yogyakarta | 2007-2009 |
|--|--------------|
| Medical Research and Science Club, Universitas Muhammadiyah Yogyakarta | 2009-2012 |
| Indonesia Medical Student Executive Board Association | 2008-2010 |
| Asia e-Health Information Network (AeHIN) | 2016-present |
| Junior Doctor Networks Indonesia | 2019-2023 |

PROJECTS

**

Improving Quality of Disease Preparedness, Surveillance & Response In Indonesia (INSPIRASI)

Funded by CDC 2021-2023

Researcher: Analyse Indonesia national health insurance claims on capability to monitor potentially outbreak infectious disease surveillance using time series analysis and data visualization. Designing dashboard presentation of infectious disease surveillance using Indonesia national health insurance claims data to support potentially outbreak infectious disease surveillance program in Indonesia. Writing scientific publication on quality of Early Warning and Response System reporting in primary health care facility. Writing policy brief on implementation of Public Health Emergency Operation Center in regional settings.

Integrated Health Surveillance System Supporting Covid-19 Emergency Response Operations

Funded by World Bank Group

2021-2022

Consultant: Analyse workflow of Allrecord TC-19, an application used by Indonesia government to collect PCR and rapid antigen result for COVID-19 surveillance. Building online user guideline for Allrecord TC-19 application to help user get the update from the app. Held two batch of one week FHIR workshops for public/private hospitals, HIMS vendors, and healthcare startups.

Evaluation of Healthcare Gaps in Indonesian Health System

African Medical and Research Foundation (AMREF)

2022

Co - Principal Investigator: Assisting Principal Investigator in conducting evaluation of healthcare system gaps with a focus on IBD, cancer, rare diseases and PDT treatment in Indonesia; Developing both quantitative and qualitative data collection methods from the stakeholders including governmental authorities, public and private healthcare providers (hospitals and primary care), healthcare NGOs, pharmaceutical companies; Coordinating field researcher in conducting data collection at national and regional level.

Post-Abortion Care Supply Chain Management Assesment in Indonesia

Funded by Ipas 2020

Consultant: Conducting Post-Abortion Care Supply Chain Management assessment in Indonesia involving MoH, public health office staffs, public health center staffs, hospital staffs, and post-abortion care logistics supplier.; Responsible for designing methodology and instruments.; Responsible for data quantitative and qualitative data collection and analysis.

Evaluation of Clinical Pathway Implementation in General Hospital in Indonesia

Funded by Research and Development Ministry of Health Indonesia

2019

Field Researcher Coordinator: Coordinating with Principal Investigator in conducting data collection in the field; Coordination with the hospital for data collection procedure; Coordination with several enumerator for

2

2/4

conduction data collection; Preparing qualitative data collection report (transription and verbatim) to Principal Investigator.

Developing Monitoring and Evaluation System for Family Planning Program in National Family Planning Coordinating Agency (BKKBN)

Funded by Bill-Melinda Gates Foundation (BMGF)

2016-2017

Information Technology Specialist: Doing needs assessment on monitoring and evaluation capacity in BKKBN. Then from the assessment result, designing monitoring and evaluation information system in national, regional, and district levels.

PUBLICATIONS

Rahmanti, A. R., Yang, H.-C., Bintoro, B. S., Nursetyo, A. A., Muhtar, M. S., Syed-Abdul, S., & Li, Y.-C. J. (2022). SlimMe, a Chatbot With Artificial Empathy for Personal Weight Management: System Design and Finding. Frontiers in Nutrition, 9, 870775. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2022.870775

Rahmanti, A. R., Chien, C.-H., Nursetyo, A. A., Husnayain, A., Wiratama, B. S., Fuad, A., Yang, H.-C., & Li, Y.-C. J. (2022). Social media sentiment analysis to monitor the performance of vaccination coverage during the early phase of the national COVID-19 vaccine rollout. Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine, 221, 106838. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmpb.2022.106838

Nanda, R. O., Nursetyo, A. A., Ramadona, A. L., Imron, M. A., Fuad, A., Setyawan, A., & Ahmad, R. A. (2022). Community Mobility and COVID-19 Dynamics in Jakarta, Indonesia. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 19(11), 6671. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph19116671

Hardhantyo, M., Djasri, H., Nursetyo, A. A., Yulianti, A., Adipradipta, B. R., Hawley, W., Mika, J., Praptiningsih, C. Y., Mangiri, A., Prasetyowati, E. B., & Brye, L. (2022). Quality of National Disease Surveillance Reporting before and during COVID-19: A Mixed-Method Study in Indonesia. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 19(5), 2728. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph19052728

Dovgan, E., Gradišek, A., Luštrek, M., Uddin, M., Nursetyo, A. A., Annavarajula, S. K., Li, Y.-C., & Syed-Abdul, S. (2020). Using machine learning models to predict the initiation of renal replacement therapy among chronic kidney disease patients. PLOS ONE, 15(6), e0233976. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0233976

Syed-Abdul, S., Malwade, S., Nursetyo, A. A., Sood, M., Bhatia, M., Barsasella, D., Liu, M. F., Chang, C.-C., Srinivasan, K., M., R., & Li, Y.-C. J. (2019). Virtual reality among the elderly: A usefulness and acceptance study from Taiwan. BMC Geriatrics, 19(1), 223. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12877-019-1218-8

Nursetyo, A. A., Syed-Abdul, S., Uddin, M., & Li, Y.-C. J. (2019). Graft Rejection Prediction Following Kidney Transplantation Using Machine Learning Techniques: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Studies in Health Technology and Informatics, 264, 10–14. https://doi.org/10.3233/SHTI190173

Putra, F. R., Nursetyo, A. A., Thakur, S. S., Roy, R. B., Syed-Abdul, S., Malwade, S., & Li, Y.-C. J. (2019). Prediction of Clinical Events in Hemodialysis Patients Using an Artificial Neural Network. Studies in Health Technology and Informatics, 264, 1570–1571. https://doi.org/10.3233/SHTI190539

Thakur, S. S., Abdul, S. S., Chiu, H.-Y. (Shannon), Roy, R. B., Huang, P.-Y., Malwade, S., Nursetyo, A. A., & Li, Y.-C. (Jack). (2018). Artificial-Intelligence-Based Prediction of Clinical Events among Hemodialysis Patients Using Non-Contact Sensor Data. Sensors, 18(9), 2833. https://doi.org/10.3390/s18092833

Ganapathy, K., Abdul, S., & Nursetyo, A. (2018). Artificial intelligence in neurosciences: A clinician's perspective. Neurology India, 66(4), 934. https://doi.org/10.4103/0028-3886.236971

Malwade, S., Abdul, S. S., Uddin, M., Nursetyo, A. A., Fernandez-Luque, L., Zhu, X. (Katie), Cilliers, L., Wong, C.-P., Bamidis, P., & Li, Y.-C. (Jack). (2018). Mobile and wearable technologies in healthcare for the ageing

3

population. Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine, 161, 233–237. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmpb. 2018.04.026

Nurwanti, E., Uddin, M., Chang, J.-S., Hadi, H., Syed-Abdul, S., Su, E., Nursetyo, A., Masud, J., & Bai, C.-H. (2018). Roles of Sedentary Behaviors and Unhealthy Foods in Increasing the Obesity Risk in Adult Men and Women: A Cross-Sectional National Study. Nutrients, 10(6), 704. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu10060704

4

4/4